{
    "id": "5949e9d6039d46de923f6485a729d584",
    "title": "Phrasal Verbs Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "The baby takes …………………….. her mother.",
            "description": "Take after = resemble",
            "answers": [
                "up",
                "for",
                "after"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "The minister was forced to take his controversial remarks …………………….",
            "description": "To take something back is to withdraw a statement.",
            "answers": [
                "off",
                "down",
                "back"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "Be careful. He might try to take you ………………………",
            "description": "To take somebody in is to cheat them.",
            "answers": [
                "out",
                "on",
                "in"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "This blouse is loose for me. I must take it ……………………….",
            "description": "To take something in is to make a garment tighter.",
            "answers": [
                "out",
                "in",
                "over"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "She was not capable of taking her children ……………………… hand",
            "description": "To take somebody in hand is to control them.",
            "answers": [
                "on",
                "in",
                "over"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "The plane is about to take …………………….. Please wear your seat belts.",
            "description": "When a plane takes off, it becomes airborne.",
            "answers": [
                "up",
                "on",
                "off"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "You must take your shoes ……………………… before entering the temple.",
            "description": "To take a piece of clothing off is to remove it.",
            "answers": [
                "up",
                "on",
                "off"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "Nobody was willing to take ………………………… the responsibility.",
            "description": "To take on is to accept.",
            "answers": [
                "in",
                "over",
                "on"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "I know you had a bad day at work, but you can’t take it ……………………….. on me.",
            "description": "To take it out on somebody is to relieve your frustration by treating someone badly.",
            "answers": [
                "out",
                "over",
                "up"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "Profits of the firm increased after she took ……………….. as the CEO.",
            "description": "To take over is to assume control of something.",
            "answers": [
                "on",
                "up",
                "over"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "The children took ……………………… their new teacher immediately.",
            "description": "To take to somebody is to start to like them.",
            "answers": [
                "to",
                "on",
                "up"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "He quit his corporate job to take …………………….. farming.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "on",
                "in",
                "up"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        }
    ]
}